anna how you doing you've been training
a lot
you've been on the wall yeah
it's too hard right but see you're
training so much now you're losing your
beginner status
i can't call you a beginner anymore but
i have one more video
idea we can do and this is going to be
super super hard
actually this is something only advanced
players do
i'm going to try it with you because i
think you're so talented you might be
able to pull this off you want to give
it a try
absolutely but i'm still a beginner i'm
telling you i don't think so i think
you're losing your beginner status
all right okay so this thing that i'm
gonna teach you today is
overheads on the wall so let me show you
how to do it and a few things that can
be beneficial from learning how to do
this is number one you're gonna be
tossing the ball to yourself
you can work on your surf toss and
overall learning how to control the ball
properly
and because the ball is going to be high
you'll have to move your feet a lot and
this is
absolutely incredible workout for your
feet and the way it's going to work
you're going to feed yourself laps look
if you hit the ball into the ground it's
going to ricochet
off the wall and it's going to go up
look like this so this is the first
thing i want you to do
you can do this in a forehand grip
actually and you just bounce the ball
into the wall
and then make it pop up into your hand
and do this a few times
stand right there and just kind of pop
the ball into the ground and make it go
up yeah you have to do it
like when you aim you would have to aim
pretty close
to the wall here in order for it to come
up
and i'll catch it do it again do it
again
closer to the wall closer to the wall
you have to bounce it closer to the wall
there you go
do it again good
that was too that was that wasn't close
enough to the wall there okay do it
again
okay remember here look look how close
to the wall i'm balancing it like this
you see where it's bouncing yeah and it
comes right at me you see that yeah
right there every time in the same place
like that
right in the round do it again
better do it again go a little longer
with the ball
yes that's it couple more good
last one so the next progression is
going to be actually keeping it in play
and here you can go into your
continental grip which is going to be
your overhead
and yeah it's going to be your overhead
grip and now basically you do the same
thing but you kind of pop it
back and forth to each other very gently
you just kind of pop the ball you don't
have to follow through
you just tap it into the ground right in
front of the wall
try it out
do it again it looks easy but it's not
it's not so easy you want to show it
again watch watch
see it's all about where you where you
hit the ball into the ground if you hit
it close enough to the wall
it's going to pop up nice and high
because that's what you want you want
the ball to turn into a lob
you see that like that
do it again here watch let's do it
together watch this
hold the racket hold the rack come a
little closer open up a little and watch
this
you got to move the feet though you got
to track the ball let's move the let's
track the ball
let's just track the ball look we're
tracking it
there it is see we're doing it
there it is okay you see
yeah there it is do it alone
do it again
closer to the wall close to the wall
there you go
there you go here it is there it is keep
going
yes excellent
very nice job
good see you're getting confidence now
excellent
good keep going wow
nice job you see what i mean you got the
rhythm now
and last one all right it's good enough
awesome it's fun right it just starts
going it goes and then you keep going
it's fun right
yeah you need someone to show you and
then once you learn how to help
when you right and then once you learn
how to do it then it's easy
okay now let's go on to the next
progression which is the actual overhead
okay so in the overhead we're going to
start from the trophy position
continental trophy position we're going
to start here and now we'll have to toss
the ball up with like we do on the
server never like continental position
i know this is very normal that you
prefer like on the serve and the
overhead is to go from the forehand
because remember our serve lesson
actually our overhead lesson you are
more comfortable by opening the racket
face up and approaching the ball with
the strings
this is something that you have to break
it's a comfort level that every beginner
has
and you have to approach the ball what's
called an edge it's going to happen
naturally as you start to
accelerate towards the ball so it's
crucial that from the beginning you do
every shot in tennis with a continental
grip except your forehand so it's going
to be your overhead it's going to be
your serve your two-handed backhand your
volleys
all with the continental grip the only
time you have to change your grip is on
the forehand okay
you start with the feed and this is how
you get the rally started now
simply move your feet and keep popping
the ball
in the same place which is very close to
the wall and now you get to keep it
in play and eventually when you get more
comfortable you start taking
bigger swings now the crucial thing on
this exercise is that
you move your feet because the ball will
not be in the same place
all the time eventually when you get
really good you can start ripping it
like this start going hard don't worry
i'm not going to hit you
and a couple more you see i'm doing it
don't worry last one ah okay so get it
started and keep it in play keep popping
it back and forth
good keep up footwork
stop it stop it okay now remember if it
goes like way off if it goes here let it
go don't don't bother with it
like once it's off the center forget
about it just start the next
rally okay and be very central here and
remember to move your feet and
watch the ball very carefully good
good good excellent
excellent come on get up i stop it now
so once you miss it
then you stop and start over okay try it
again that was really good the first
first try was excellent
here we go keep going come on okay stop
it stop it yeah i keep forgetting that
it shouldn't
hit the ground that's what mixes me up
what do you mean
well i feel like it has to oh no it
doesn't hit the ground
you take the ball in the air i'm waiting
for it there is such a thing as uh
overhead that bounces but in this
instance you take everything in the air
okay
yeah all right try it again
good good come on go get it nice
that was amazing you got to go back and
forth a little bit do a racket tap
on that one and now can you try to go a
little bit harder
you know what i mean by that so go maybe
a little further back
and you're going to swing a little bit
harder into the ground like this
you give it a little bit more steam like
that
okay give it a try
you look forward don't bend there's a
lot of rules i know
go and a hard come on
ah sideways sideways you look one thing
that's very important is that you
maintain a sideways position the whole
time
like you will open up after you hit the
overhead but then go back to being
sideways when you're tracking the ball
very important look
when the ball's in the air i'm sideways
look i'm sideways tracking the ball
this is very important like don't track
the ball like this because it's very
uncomfortable to move this way so as the
ball is in the air
you're going to be in a sideways
position your chin is going to be
over your left shoulder like this
okay chin over the left shoulder
come good come on good
good come on hit it hit it
come on amazing
all right you know what i gotta tell you
that was amazing good job